ford.com.au 2018-09-15

# Ford Australia - Privacy

Ford Motor Company of Australia Limited  
Privacy Policy  
Version date: August 2018

  1. Introduction
  2. What is personal information?
  3. What types of personal information does Ford collect?
  4. How do we collect your personal information?
  5. For what purposes do we collect, use and disclose your personal information?
  6. What happens if you don't provide personal information?
  7. To whom do we disclose personal information?
  8. Does personal information leave Australia? 
  9. How do we protect personal information?
  10. What about information you provide in job applications?
  11. Is the personal information we hold accurate?
  12. Links, cookies and use of the Ford website
  13. How you can access and correct personal information we hold about you
  14. Queries, comments and complaints about our handling of personal information
  15. Contact details

1\. Introduction  
1.1 Ford Motor Company of Australia Limited ABN 30 004 116 223 (“Ford”, “we”, “our” and “us”) is committed to responsible privacy practices and to complying with the Privacy Principles contained in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (“Privacy Act”). Where applicable, Ford will handle personal information relying on the related bodies corporate exemption and the employee records exemption in the Privacy Act and any other applicable exemptions in the Privacy Act or other legislation.

1.2 This Privacy Policy sets out our policies on the management of personal information including how we collect personal information, the purposes for which we use this information, and to whom this information is disclosed.

1.3 Authorised Ford Dealers (“Dealers”) are independent entities and not related to Ford and may have privacy policies which differ from ours. Dealers are responsible for their own privacy policies and privacy practices. Please contact your Dealer directly for further information.

1.4 We may change our Privacy Policy from time to time at our discretion. At any time, the latest version of our Privacy Policy is available from our website at www.ford.com.au or from our Customer Relationship Centre.

Back to Top

2\. What is personal information?  
2.1 In this Privacy Policy, “personal information” has the meaning set out in the Privacy Act. Essentially, personal information is information or an opinion about an individual who is reasonably identifiable.

Back to Top

3\. What types of personal information does Ford collect?  
3.1 The types of personal information Ford collects from you depend on the circumstances in which the information is collected.

3.2 Ford may collect contact details including your name, address, email address and phone and fax numbers.

3.3 Where relevant, Ford may also collect your driver’s licence and registration details, date of birth or age group, occupation, gender, information about your vehicle (including its number plate and vehicle identification number), answers you provide to questions we ask and other information in relation to your dealings with Ford or Dealers (such as types of vehicle purchased and replaced and repair/service history).

3.4 If you are an individual contractor to Ford, in addition to the information referred to in section 3.3 we may collect information relevant to your engagement with Ford including qualifications, length of engagement, resume, pay rate and salary, bank details, feedback from supervisors, training records and logs of your usage of Ford equipment (e.g. phones, computers and vehicles). A reference to an individual contractor in this document includes those individuals who perform work for Ford under a “purchased service” arrangement. If you are employed by or contracted to a Dealer, we may also collect and maintain training records about you.

3.5 When using the Ford website, we or our third party service providers may collect web site usage information such as the IP address you are using, the name of your Internet service provider, your browser version, the web site that referred you to us and the next website you go to, the pages you request, the date and time of those requests and the country you are in. Except where you provide it to us via the website, we do not collect personal information such as your name, mailing address, email address or phone number when you are browsing our website.

3.6 Ford does not generally require customers to disclose any sensitive information (e.g. details of race, religious beliefs, sexual orientation, health information etc.) to us. In limited circumstances, we may require prospective employees, individual contractors and Dealer personnel to provide us with certain health information. See section 10 of this Privacy Policy for further details.

3.7 If you do provide sensitive information to us for any reason (for example, if you provide us with information about a disability you have), you consent to us collecting that information and to us using and disclosing that information for the purpose for which you disclosed it to us and as permitted by the Privacy Act and other relevant laws.

3.8 Occasionally, sensitive information in relation to an individual’s membership of a trade or similar association may be provided to us but we do not actively seek this information. We will only use and disclose that information for the purpose for which you disclosed it to us and as permitted by the Privacy Act and other relevant laws.

3.9 In addition to the types of personal information identified above, Ford may collect personal information as otherwise permitted or required by law.

Back to Top

4\. How do we collect your personal information?  
4.1 Ford collects personal information in a number of ways. The most common ways we collect your personal information are:

  * directly from you when you provide it to us or our agents or contractors (e.g. via our Customer Relationship Centre);
  * via Dealers from which you purchase Ford related goods or services;
  * via our website or when you deal with us online (including through social media);
  * via our market research agencies;
  * when you enter a competition or promotion;
  * if you are an individual contractor to Ford, from your employer or recruitment agency;
  * if you are employed by or contracted to a Dealer, from that Dealer;
  * via in-vehicle technologies (e.g. SYNC system analytics and diagnostics features);
  * via the SYNC owners forum;
  * from publicly available sources;
  * from our related companies; and
  * from third parties (for example, from referees if you apply for a position as an employee or contractor with us).

Back to Top

5\. For what purposes do we collect, use and disclose your personal information?  
5.1 The purposes for which we use and disclose your personal information will depend on the circumstances in which we collect it. Whenever practical we endeavour to inform you why we are collecting your personal information, how we intend to use that information and to whom we intend to disclose it at the time we collect your personal information.

5.2 We may use or disclose your personal information:

  * for the purposes for which we collected it (and related purposes which would be reasonably expected by you);
  * for other purposes to which you have consented; and
  * as otherwise authorised or required by law.

5.3 In general we collect, use and disclose your personal information so that we can do business together and for purposes connected with our business operations.

5.4 Some of the specific purposes for which we collect, use and disclose personal information are as follows:

  * to facilitate your request for a brochure or test drive, to add you to a mailing list or to respond if you request information (including via the Ford website or via an email you send to us);
  * to record and maintain the details of your purchase of a Ford vehicle for warranty purposes or your purchase of a "myFord" product or service for administration purposes;
  * to keep track of the repairs and servicing of your Ford vehicle by Dealers;
  * to facilitate the provision of roadside assistance and other services you acquire from us, Dealers or our agents or contractors;
  * to inform you in the event of a field service action, for example a recall, affecting your Ford vehicle;
  * to issue service reminders;
  * to improve our products and services;
  * to help us identify and diagnose SYNC system usage and performance issues for quality assurance purposes and to improve our products and services;
  * to contact you (directly or through our service providers and marketing research agencies) to obtain your feedback and to find out your level of satisfaction with our products, services and Dealers through surveys;
  * to report to and evaluate Dealers;
  * to verify your identity;
  * to facilitate your entry and participation in a competition or trade promotion;
  * to consider you for a job at Ford (whether as an employee or contractor) or other relationships with us;
  * to provide goods or services to you or to receive goods or services from you;
  * to address any issues or complaints that we or you have regarding our relationship; and
  * to contact you regarding the above, including via electronic messaging such as SMS and email, by mail, by phone or in any other lawful manner.

5.5 We may also use and disclose your personal information for the purpose of direct marketing to you where:

  * you have consented to us doing so; or
  * it is otherwise permitted by law.

5.6 Direct marketing involves communicating directly with you for the purpose of promoting goods or services to you and to provide you with special offers from Ford or its Dealers. Direct marketing can be delivered by a range of methods including mail, telephone, email or SMS. You can unsubscribe from our direct marketing, or change your contact preferences, by contacting us (see section 15 of this Privacy Policy). If you wish to unsubscribe from direct marketing you have received from a Dealer, please contact that Dealer directly.

Back to Top

6\. What happens if you don't provide personal information?  
6.1 Generally, you have no obligation to provide any personal information requested by us. However, if you choose to withhold requested personal information, we may not be able to provide you with the products and services that depend on the collection of that information.  
6.2 As an example, if we did not collect personal information about your new vehicle purchase, we would be unable to notify you directly of a product recall affecting your vehicle.  

Back to Top

7\. To whom do we disclose personal information?  
7.1 We may disclose your personal information to third parties in connection with the purposes described in section 5 of this Privacy Policy.

7.2 This may include disclosing your personal information to the following types of third parties:

  * Dealers;
  * our related companies;
  * our contractors (including mailing houses, marketing agencies, insurance providers, website and data hosting providers and other IT suppliers);
  * other persons who perform services for, or in connection with, us (including to facilitate the delivery of purchases, to provide roadside assistance, to autoclubs, for electronic direct mailing, for credit card payment authorisation, for trend analysis, for market research, for promotions and for the provision of statistical sales information to industry bodies);
  * companies who may use your personal information in order to tailor electronic advertising to you (e.g. on a webpage) in relation to our products and services;
  * our accountants, insurers (including those that provide extended warranties), lawyers, auditors and other professional advisers;
  * if you are an individual contractor to Ford, to your employer or agency in relation to the performance of your work with Ford;
  * if you are an individual contractor to Ford or a prospective employee, to our medical service providers for any medical assessments or in relation to any health or safety incidents and to HR related service providers (e.g. for background checks, screening or aptitude testing);
  * any third parties to whom you have directed or permitted us to disclose your personal information (e.g. referees);
  * in the unlikely event that we or our assets may be acquired or considered for acquisition by a third party, that third party and its advisors;
  * third parties that require the information for law enforcement or to prevent a serious threat to public safety; and
  * otherwise as permitted or required by law.

7.3 Where we disclose your personal information to third parties we will use reasonable commercial efforts to ensure that such third parties only use your personal information as reasonably required for the purpose we disclosed it to them and in a manner consistent with the Privacy Principles under the Privacy Act, e.g. by (where commercially practical) including suitable privacy and confidentiality clauses in our agreement with a third party service provider to which we disclose your personal information.

7.4 If you post information to certain public parts of our website or to our social media pages, you acknowledge that such information may be available to be viewed by the public. You should use discretion in deciding what information you upload to such sites.

7.5 Your personal information will not be “sold” by Ford to any other organisation for that organisation's unrelated independent use. If you have opted in to receive marketing materials from Ford, we may share anonymised “hashed” data with social media advertising partners, such as Facebook, so that they can create Custom Audiences and deliver advertisements on our behalf to their members. Members are identifiable when the Social Media partner matches our anonymised data to its anonymised data of its users.

Back to Top

8\. Does personal information leave Australia?  
8.1 Some of the third parties to whom we disclose personal information may be located outside Australia. For example, we may disclose personal information to our related companies overseas and to our overseas service providers.

8.2 The countries in which these third parties are located will depend on the circumstances. In the ordinary course of business we commonly disclose personal information to parties located in the United States, India, China and Singapore (where our Ford group data and business centres are located). Except where an exception applies under the Privacy Act, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that such overseas recipients do not breach the Privacy Principles in the Privacy Act in relation to such information.

Back to Top

9\. How do we protect personal information?  
9.1 Ford will take reasonable steps to keep any personal information we hold about you secure. However, except to the extent liability cannot be excluded due to the operation of statute, we exclude all liability (including in negligence) for the consequences of any unauthorised access to, disclosure of, misuse of or loss or corruption of your personal information. Nothing in this Privacy Policy restricts, excludes or modifies or purports to restrict, exclude or modify any statutory consumer rights under any applicable law including the Competition and Consumer Act 2010 (Cth). Please notify us immediately if you become aware of any breach of security.

Back to Top

10\. What about information you provide in job applications?  
10.1 If you submit a job application to Ford, we will use the information provided by you to assess your application. Ford may disclose the information contained in your application to contracted service providers for purposes such as screening, aptitude testing, medical testing and human resources management activities.

10.2 As part of the application process or (if you are successful in being employed by Ford) after you commence employment with Ford, you may be required to complete a health questionnaire. You may also be asked to undergo a medical assessment. In that case, you will be asked to give specific consent for Ford to disclose your questionnaire to its service providers for the purposes of the medical assessment and for the relevant service providers to disclose the results of the assessment to Ford.

10.3 If you refuse to provide any of the information requested by Ford, or to consent to Ford disclosing your questionnaire to its service providers for the purpose of a medical assessment or to the disclosure of the results of your medical assessment to Ford, we may be unable to consider your application (or if you have been successful in being employed by Ford, we may not be able to consider you for particular roles or positions within Ford).

10.4 Ford will handle health information in accordance with applicable laws and our Health Information Policy.

10.5 Ford may also ask you whether you agree to your personal information being provided to appropriate Ford suppliers so that you may be considered for positions with those suppliers which are relevant to your qualifications and experience.

Back to Top

11\. Is the personal information we hold accurate?  
11.1 We endeavour to maintain your personal information as accurately as reasonably possible. We rely on the accuracy of personal information as provided to us both directly (from you) and indirectly (e.g. from a Dealer).

11.2 We encourage you to contact us if the personal information we hold about you is incorrect or to notify us of a change in your personal information. Our contact details are set out in section 15 of this Privacy Policy.

Back to Top

12\. Links, cookies and use of the Ford website  
12.1 The Ford website contains links to other sites. This Privacy Policy applies to the Ford website and not any linked sites. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of each website that collects your personal information.

12.2 Ford and its third party service providers and / or advertising partners uses web tracking and storage technology tools such as web beacons, "cookies", "pixel tags" and java code on Ford websites and in emails you have agreed to receive from us to collect or receive information regarding your activities on the site (eg. your IP address, page(s) visited, time of day). The use of such technology is an industry standard, and helps monitor the effectiveness of advertising and how visitors use websites. A "cookie" is a small data element stored by your web browser on your computer system. If selected by you, the Ford websites will store your username and password in a "cookie" to enable you to be automatically logged in when you return.

12.3 We, our third party service providers and / or advertising partners use this technology to generate statistics and measure site activity to improve the usefulness of customer visits.

12.4 Each time you access Ford websites, Ford and its third party service providers and / or advertising partners may deliver certain customised information, including ads, to you based on the data stored in your cookie. Third party advertising partners may show our ads on sites on the Internet and serve these ads based on information they collected about a user’s prior visits to our website and other Internet activity. Ford may also use analytics data supplied by third party vendors to inform and optimise our ad campaigns. This practice is commonly referred to as "interest-based advertising".

12.5 Opting out of Interest-Based Advertising: You may learn about how to opt-out of this kind of collection and use of information for your browser or device by managing your settings, and for your social media accounts by managing your preferences in your account settings.

12.6 Opting out from specific advertisers: Facebook: To learn more about how to opt out of Facebook Interest-Based Advertising, go to the Privacy tab on the Facebook website footer, and then select Facebook Ads Controls.

Back to Top

13\. How you can access and correct personal information we hold about you  
13.1 You may seek access to personal information which Ford holds about you by contacting us as described in section 15 of this Privacy Policy. We will provide access to that information in accordance with the Privacy Act, subject to certain exemptions which may apply. We may require that the person requesting access provide suitable identification and where permitted by law we may charge an administration fee for granting access to your personal information.

13.2 If you become aware that any personal information we hold about you is incorrect or if you wish to update your information, please contact Ford (see section 15 of this Privacy Policy).

13.3 If you wish to access, correct or update personal information held by a Dealer, or unsubscribe from direct marketing from the Dealer, please contact that Dealer directly.

Back to Top

14\. Queries, comments and complaints about our handling of personal information  
14.1 If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about our collection, use or disclosure of personal information, or if you believe that we have not complied with this Privacy Policy or the Privacy Act, please contact us (see section 15 of this Privacy Policy).  
14.2 When contacting us please provide as much detail as possible in relation to your question, concern or complaint.

14.3 Ford will take any privacy complaint seriously and any complaint will be assessed by an appropriate person with the aim of resolving any issue in a timely and efficient manner. We request that you cooperate with us during this process and provide us with any relevant information that we may need.

14.4 If you are not satisfied with the outcome of our assessment of your complaint, you may wish to contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (click [here](https://www.ford.com.au/forms/privacy-complaints.html) for information).

Back to Top

15\. Contact details  
15.1 Please address all privacy complaints to:  
Attention: Privacy Officer  
Ford Motor Company of Australia Limited  
Private Mail Bag 6  
Campbellfield VIC 3061  
OR  

15.2 If you wish to seek access to or correct or update any personal information we hold about you, or to unsubscribe from or change your contact preferences in relation to our direct marketing, you can also contact us as follows:

  * phone the Ford Customer Relationship Centre on 13FORD (13 36 73);
  * fax the Ford Customer Relationship Centre on (03) 9929 3075; or
  * email us at [foacust1@ford.com](mailto:foacust1@ford.com).

Ford Motor Company of Australia Limited  
Privacy Policy  
Version date: August 2018

  1. Introduction
  2. What is personal information?
  3. What types of personal information does Ford collect?
  4. How do we collect your personal information?
  5. For what purposes do we collect, use and disclose your personal information?
  6. What happens if you don't provide personal information?
  7. To whom do we disclose personal information?
  8. Does personal information leave Australia? 
  9. How do we protect personal information?
  10. What about information you provide in job applications?
  11. Is the personal information we hold accurate?
  12. Links, cookies and use of the Ford website
  13. How you can access and correct personal information we hold about you
  14. Queries, comments and complaints about our handling of personal information
  15. Contact details

1\. Introduction  
1.1 Ford Motor Company of Australia Limited ABN 30 004 116 223 (“Ford”, “we”, “our” and “us”) is committed to responsible privacy practices and to complying with the Privacy Principles contained in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (“Privacy Act”). Where applicable, Ford will handle personal information relying on the related bodies corporate exemption and the employee records exemption in the Privacy Act and any other applicable exemptions in the Privacy Act or other legislation.

1.2 This Privacy Policy sets out our policies on the management of personal information including how we collect personal information, the purposes for which we use this information, and to whom this information is disclosed.

1.3 Authorised Ford Dealers (“Dealers”) are independent entities and not related to Ford and may have privacy policies which differ from ours. Dealers are responsible for their own privacy policies and privacy practices. Please contact your Dealer directly for further information.

1.4 We may change our Privacy Policy from time to time at our discretion. At any time, the latest version of our Privacy Policy is available from our website at www.ford.com.au or from our Customer Relationship Centre.

Back to Top

2\. What is personal information?  
2.1 In this Privacy Policy, “personal information” has the meaning set out in the Privacy Act. Essentially, personal information is information or an opinion about an individual who is reasonably identifiable.

Back to Top

3\. What types of personal information does Ford collect?  
3.1 The types of personal information Ford collects from you depend on the circumstances in which the information is collected.

3.2 Ford may collect contact details including your name, address, email address and phone and fax numbers.

3.3 Where relevant, Ford may also collect your driver’s licence and registration details, date of birth or age group, occupation, gender, information about your vehicle (including its number plate and vehicle identification number), answers you provide to questions we ask and other information in relation to your dealings with Ford or Dealers (such as types of vehicle purchased and replaced and repair/service history).

3.4 If you are an individual contractor to Ford, in addition to the information referred to in section 3.3 we may collect information relevant to your engagement with Ford including qualifications, length of engagement, resume, pay rate and salary, bank details, feedback from supervisors, training records and logs of your usage of Ford equipment (e.g. phones, computers and vehicles). A reference to an individual contractor in this document includes those individuals who perform work for Ford under a “purchased service” arrangement. If you are employed by or contracted to a Dealer, we may also collect and maintain training records about you.

3.5 When using the Ford website, we or our third party service providers may collect web site usage information such as the IP address you are using, the name of your Internet service provider, your browser version, the web site that referred you to us and the next website you go to, the pages you request, the date and time of those requests and the country you are in. Except where you provide it to us via the website, we do not collect personal information such as your name, mailing address, email address or phone number when you are browsing our website.

3.6 Ford does not generally require customers to disclose any sensitive information (e.g. details of race, religious beliefs, sexual orientation, health information etc.) to us. In limited circumstances, we may require prospective employees, individual contractors and Dealer personnel to provide us with certain health information. See section 10 of this Privacy Policy for further details.

3.7 If you do provide sensitive information to us for any reason (for example, if you provide us with information about a disability you have), you consent to us collecting that information and to us using and disclosing that information for the purpose for which you disclosed it to us and as permitted by the Privacy Act and other relevant laws.

3.8 Occasionally, sensitive information in relation to an individual’s membership of a trade or similar association may be provided to us but we do not actively seek this information. We will only use and disclose that information for the purpose for which you disclosed it to us and as permitted by the Privacy Act and other relevant laws.

3.9 In addition to the types of personal information identified above, Ford may collect personal information as otherwise permitted or required by law.

Back to Top

4\. How do we collect your personal information?  
4.1 Ford collects personal information in a number of ways. The most common ways we collect your personal information are:

  * directly from you when you provide it to us or our agents or contractors (e.g. via our Customer Relationship Centre);
  * via Dealers from which you purchase Ford related goods or services;
  * via our website or when you deal with us online (including through social media);
  * via our market research agencies;
  * when you enter a competition or promotion;
  * if you are an individual contractor to Ford, from your employer or recruitment agency;
  * if you are employed by or contracted to a Dealer, from that Dealer;
  * via in-vehicle technologies (e.g. SYNC system analytics and diagnostics features);
  * via the SYNC owners forum;
  * from publicly available sources;
  * from our related companies; and
  * from third parties (for example, from referees if you apply for a position as an employee or contractor with us).

Back to Top

5\. For what purposes do we collect, use and disclose your personal information?  
5.1 The purposes for which we use and disclose your personal information will depend on the circumstances in which we collect it. Whenever practical we endeavour to inform you why we are collecting your personal information, how we intend to use that information and to whom we intend to disclose it at the time we collect your personal information.

5.2 We may use or disclose your personal information:

  * for the purposes for which we collected it (and related purposes which would be reasonably expected by you);
  * for other purposes to which you have consented; and
  * as otherwise authorised or required by law.

5.3 In general we collect, use and disclose your personal information so that we can do business together and for purposes connected with our business operations.

5.4 Some of the specific purposes for which we collect, use and disclose personal information are as follows:

  * to facilitate your request for a brochure or test drive, to add you to a mailing list or to respond if you request information (including via the Ford website or via an email you send to us);
  * to record and maintain the details of your purchase of a Ford vehicle for warranty purposes or your purchase of a "myFord" product or service for administration purposes;
  * to keep track of the repairs and servicing of your Ford vehicle by Dealers;
  * to facilitate the provision of roadside assistance and other services you acquire from us, Dealers or our agents or contractors;
  * to inform you in the event of a field service action, for example a recall, affecting your Ford vehicle;
  * to issue service reminders;
  * to improve our products and services;
  * to help us identify and diagnose SYNC system usage and performance issues for quality assurance purposes and to improve our products and services;
  * to contact you (directly or through our service providers and marketing research agencies) to obtain your feedback and to find out your level of satisfaction with our products, services and Dealers through surveys;
  * to report to and evaluate Dealers;
  * to verify your identity;
  * to facilitate your entry and participation in a competition or trade promotion;
  * to consider you for a job at Ford (whether as an employee or contractor) or other relationships with us;
  * to provide goods or services to you or to receive goods or services from you;
  * to address any issues or complaints that we or you have regarding our relationship; and
  * to contact you regarding the above, including via electronic messaging such as SMS and email, by mail, by phone or in any other lawful manner.

5.5 We may also use and disclose your personal information for the purpose of direct marketing to you where:

  * you have consented to us doing so; or
  * it is otherwise permitted by law.

5.6 Direct marketing involves communicating directly with you for the purpose of promoting goods or services to you and to provide you with special offers from Ford or its Dealers. Direct marketing can be delivered by a range of methods including mail, telephone, email or SMS. You can unsubscribe from our direct marketing, or change your contact preferences, by contacting us (see section 15 of this Privacy Policy). If you wish to unsubscribe from direct marketing you have received from a Dealer, please contact that Dealer directly.

Back to Top

6\. What happens if you don't provide personal information?  
6.1 Generally, you have no obligation to provide any personal information requested by us. However, if you choose to withhold requested personal information, we may not be able to provide you with the products and services that depend on the collection of that information.  
6.2 As an example, if we did not collect personal information about your new vehicle purchase, we would be unable to notify you directly of a product recall affecting your vehicle.  

Back to Top

7\. To whom do we disclose personal information?  
7.1 We may disclose your personal information to third parties in connection with the purposes described in section 5 of this Privacy Policy.

7.2 This may include disclosing your personal information to the following types of third parties:

  * Dealers;
  * our related companies;
  * our contractors (including mailing houses, marketing agencies, insurance providers, website and data hosting providers and other IT suppliers);
  * other persons who perform services for, or in connection with, us (including to facilitate the delivery of purchases, to provide roadside assistance, to autoclubs, for electronic direct mailing, for credit card payment authorisation, for trend analysis, for market research, for promotions and for the provision of statistical sales information to industry bodies);
  * companies who may use your personal information in order to tailor electronic advertising to you (e.g. on a webpage) in relation to our products and services;
  * our accountants, insurers (including those that provide extended warranties), lawyers, auditors and other professional advisers;
  * if you are an individual contractor to Ford, to your employer or agency in relation to the performance of your work with Ford;
  * if you are an individual contractor to Ford or a prospective employee, to our medical service providers for any medical assessments or in relation to any health or safety incidents and to HR related service providers (e.g. for background checks, screening or aptitude testing);
  * any third parties to whom you have directed or permitted us to disclose your personal information (e.g. referees);
  * in the unlikely event that we or our assets may be acquired or considered for acquisition by a third party, that third party and its advisors;
  * third parties that require the information for law enforcement or to prevent a serious threat to public safety; and
  * otherwise as permitted or required by law.

7.3 Where we disclose your personal information to third parties we will use reasonable commercial efforts to ensure that such third parties only use your personal information as reasonably required for the purpose we disclosed it to them and in a manner consistent with the Privacy Principles under the Privacy Act, e.g. by (where commercially practical) including suitable privacy and confidentiality clauses in our agreement with a third party service provider to which we disclose your personal information.

7.4 If you post information to certain public parts of our website or to our social media pages, you acknowledge that such information may be available to be viewed by the public. You should use discretion in deciding what information you upload to such sites.

7.5 Your personal information will not be “sold” by Ford to any other organisation for that organisation's unrelated independent use. If you have opted in to receive marketing materials from Ford, we may share anonymised “hashed” data with social media advertising partners, such as Facebook, so that they can create Custom Audiences and deliver advertisements on our behalf to their members. Members are identifiable when the Social Media partner matches our anonymised data to its anonymised data of its users.

Back to Top

8\. Does personal information leave Australia?  
8.1 Some of the third parties to whom we disclose personal information may be located outside Australia. For example, we may disclose personal information to our related companies overseas and to our overseas service providers.

8.2 The countries in which these third parties are located will depend on the circumstances. In the ordinary course of business we commonly disclose personal information to parties located in the United States, India, China and Singapore (where our Ford group data and business centres are located). Except where an exception applies under the Privacy Act, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that such overseas recipients do not breach the Privacy Principles in the Privacy Act in relation to such information.

Back to Top

9\. How do we protect personal information?  
9.1 Ford will take reasonable steps to keep any personal information we hold about you secure. However, except to the extent liability cannot be excluded due to the operation of statute, we exclude all liability (including in negligence) for the consequences of any unauthorised access to, disclosure of, misuse of or loss or corruption of your personal information. Nothing in this Privacy Policy restricts, excludes or modifies or purports to restrict, exclude or modify any statutory consumer rights under any applicable law including the Competition and Consumer Act 2010 (Cth). Please notify us immediately if you become aware of any breach of security.  

Back to Top

10\. What about information you provide in job applications?  
10.1 If you submit a job application to Ford, we will use the information provided by you to assess your application. Ford may disclose the information contained in your application to contracted service providers for purposes such as screening, aptitude testing, medical testing and human resources management activities.

10.2 As part of the application process or (if you are successful in being employed by Ford) after you commence employment with Ford, you may be required to complete a health questionnaire. You may also be asked to undergo a medical assessment. In that case, you will be asked to give specific consent for Ford to disclose your questionnaire to its service providers for the purposes of the medical assessment and for the relevant service providers to disclose the results of the assessment to Ford.

10.3 If you refuse to provide any of the information requested by Ford, or to consent to Ford disclosing your questionnaire to its service providers for the purpose of a medical assessment or to the disclosure of the results of your medical assessment to Ford, we may be unable to consider your application (or if you have been successful in being employed by Ford, we may not be able to consider you for particular roles or positions within Ford).

10.4 Ford will handle health information in accordance with applicable laws and our Health Information Policy.

10.5 Ford may also ask you whether you agree to your personal information being provided to appropriate Ford suppliers so that you may be considered for positions with those suppliers which are relevant to your qualifications and experience.

Back to Top

11\. Is the personal information we hold accurate?  
11.1 We endeavour to maintain your personal information as accurately as reasonably possible. We rely on the accuracy of personal information as provided to us both directly (from you) and indirectly (e.g. from a Dealer).

11.2 We encourage you to contact us if the personal information we hold about you is incorrect or to notify us of a change in your personal information. Our contact details are set out in section 15 of this Privacy Policy.

Back to Top

12\. Links, cookies and use of the Ford website  
12.1 The Ford website contains links to other sites. This Privacy Policy applies to the Ford website and not any linked sites. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of each website that collects your personal information.

12.2 Ford and its third party service providers and / or advertising partners uses web tracking and storage technology tools such as web beacons, "cookies", "pixel tags" and java code on Ford websites and in emails you have agreed to receive from us to collect or receive information regarding your activities on the site (eg. your IP address, page(s) visited, time of day). The use of such technology is an industry standard, and helps monitor the effectiveness of advertising and how visitors use websites. A "cookie" is a small data element stored by your web browser on your computer system. If selected by you, the Ford websites will store your username and password in a "cookie" to enable you to be automatically logged in when you return.

12.3 We, our third party service providers and / or advertising partners use this technology to generate statistics and measure site activity to improve the usefulness of customer visits.

12.4 Each time you access Ford websites, Ford and its third party service providers and / or advertising partners may deliver certain customised information, including ads, to you based on the data stored in your cookie. Third party advertising partners may show our ads on sites on the Internet and serve these ads based on information they collected about a user’s prior visits to our website and other Internet activity. Ford may also use analytics data supplied by third party vendors to inform and optimise our ad campaigns. This practice is commonly referred to as "interest-based advertising".

12.5 Opting out of Interest-Based Advertising: You may learn about how to opt-out of this kind of collection and use of information for your browser or device by managing your settings, and for your social media accounts by managing your preferences in your account settings.

12.6 Opting out from specific advertisers: Facebook: To learn more about how to opt out of Facebook Interest-Based Advertising, go to the Privacy tab on the Facebook website footer, and then select Facebook Ads Controls.

Back to Top

13\. How you can access and correct personal information we hold about you  
13.1 You may seek access to personal information which Ford holds about you by contacting us as described in section 15 of this Privacy Policy. We will provide access to that information in accordance with the Privacy Act, subject to certain exemptions which may apply. We may require that the person requesting access provide suitable identification and where permitted by law we may charge an administration fee for granting access to your personal information.

13.2 If you become aware that any personal information we hold about you is incorrect or if you wish to update your information, please contact Ford (see section 15 of this Privacy Policy).

13.3 If you wish to access, correct or update personal information held by a Dealer, or unsubscribe from direct marketing from the Dealer, please contact that Dealer directly.

Back to Top

14\. Queries, comments and complaints about our handling of personal information  
14.1 If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about our collection, use or disclosure of personal information, or if you believe that we have not complied with this Privacy Policy or the Privacy Act, please contact us (see section 15 of this Privacy Policy).  
14.2 When contacting us please provide as much detail as possible in relation to your question, concern or complaint.

14.3 Ford will take any privacy complaint seriously and any complaint will be assessed by an appropriate person with the aim of resolving any issue in a timely and efficient manner. We request that you cooperate with us during this process and provide us with any relevant information that we may need.

14.4 If you are not satisfied with the outcome of our assessment of your complaint, you may wish to contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (click [here](https://www.ford.com.au/forms/privacy-complaints.html) for information).

Back to Top

15\. Contact details  
15.1 Please address all privacy complaints to:  
Attention: Privacy Officer  
Ford Motor Company of Australia Limited  
Private Mail Bag 6  
Campbellfield VIC 3061  
OR  

15.2 If you wish to seek access to or correct or update any personal information we hold about you, or to unsubscribe from or change your contact preferences in relation to our direct marketing, you can also contact us as follows:

  * phone the Ford Customer Relationship Centre on 13FORD (13 36 73);
  * fax the Ford Customer Relationship Centre on (03) 9929 3075; or
  * email us at [foacust1@ford.com](mailto:foacust1@ford.com).
